Okay.
Um, but I spend the majority of my time in Colorado, and I'm only in
Chicago about a week, a month.
Oh, okay, okay, okay, cool, cool.
Yeah.
I am. I'm very close to him, like…
You're… you're more… you're closer to the… to the mountains, I believe, right? And in Colorado. Yeah.
I'm, like, 2 miles from the mountains, right here.
Yeah.
Nice, nice, nice. That's awesome, that's awesome.
Yeah, thank you. Um…
Oh, cool
Where you… where are you out of?
Yeah.
I'm actually in Canada. I'm in Alberta. I'm also close to the mountains, in the west, in Calgary.
Okay, cool.
Yeah, yeah.
Good stuff. But, uh, yeah, just so it's not confusing, our company's out of…
Illinois, um…
But I'm not… I'm not there all that much.
Got it, got it. Okay.
Oh.
So, yeah. Um, I don't think Stefan is probably gonna join. I do see his note takers in here, but uh…
Okay.
I don't think we're waiting on him.
For this one, um, me showing you guys the function of it probably isn't that.
important for him. So, is, uh… is it just…
you and Zaheer coming, or are we waiting for everybody else?
Yeah.
Okay, cool. Okay.
Okay, good.
Yeah, no, I think we're good. We should be good to get started. Yep. And also before that, before you jump in, I do want to mention that first of all, thank you for sending in that document. That was really, really helpful to kind of understand what are the features
And actually, thanks for being very thorough, I must say, because a lot of the, you know, like, the clients, they do have a kind of vision, but I felt like you were able to, like, really write it down, which really… which is really going to help us exactly what you're looking for, right?
Good. Well, I'm Glenn.
So that was super helpful, yeah.
Yeah, no, thank you, uh…
I'm glad, and I did an okay job getting it on paper, and uh…
I figure if we're gonna actually make something work together, which I…
I'm very hopeful we can, uh, I better give a good job a…
Telling you guys what we're… what we're shooting for, so… yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah, no, for sure. I mean, I do have some questions on that, but I'll actually, I might bring up those questions because I'm pretty sure as you're walking through those things will come up. So I'll just, I have a note on my end what questions we need to clarify. But as you're kind of walking through, I'll bring those up as it comes
Yeah. Awesome. Um, are you… do you want me to just share my screen?
Sure, yeah, yeah. Basically, the idea being that, yeah, I think one thing that what we wanted to really understand is kind of walkthrough of what you do on a daily basis because I know you mentioned different platforms that you use for your business currency right now, which we intend to or which we want to integrate
Yep.
If we can, on our platform. Yeah, just kind of a walkthrough, what do you do for, like, the leads pipeline that you mentioned in the doc for the CRM functionality and the other stuff, I think that'd be great
Yep, okay, awesome. Um…
I… are you able to see my screen right now?
Yes.
Yeah. Are you seeing a HubSpot screen?
I believe, yes, it's HubSpot screen. Yep, yep.
Okay, it says, good afternoon, Nick, at the top.
Good afternoon, Nick. Yep,
Okay, so I can't actually…
it's not showing me what you guys are seeing, um…
So, which I…
I don't need to see it as you guys see it, I just…
let me know if I start talking about something that it looks like you're not…
Oh yeah, for sure.
Same as what you're seeing, but…
For sure.
Um, so the…
the CRM…
And pipeline feature is…
is kind of the…
We use all that right now in HubSpot.
Housecall Pros pipeline feature is terrible and doesn't give us the functionality that we need.
Um… so, we'll start in HubSpot, and then we'll move to Housecall Pro in a minute.
But ideally, I think the…
And you… I'm sure you guys will…
have better ideas as you learn more, but to me, the simple…
function that ties everything together would be best if it's the pipeline feature itself.
So, right now,
Um…
This is loading here, but…
When we go…
Man, my internet is being really slow, so hopefully, uh…
Hopefully that improves, but…
It has a category tag if it's residential, commercial or industrial right now we just lump everything into two different pipelines. So in reality, we've got a residential pipeline and a
Pipeline we call industrial, but actually has our commercial and industrial stuff in it.
And then I like
Go ahead.
Sorry, just a quick question. Is it fair to basically classify these pipelines as prospects
So
for… for, like, the different domains, like industrial versus residential, am I understanding that correctly?
Prospect
To me terminology
Got it
Okay.
is really important because like the way we use the word prospect is actually different than the way we use the word lead or the way we use opportunity. I think kind of a general
Overview would be like
Sure, okay.
Well, I'm not sure how to answer that yet. Let me run through the different stages and maybe
Then we can
Sure. Yep, for sure.
Get better at wording. To me
So what we call a prospect
You won't see in this pipeline. It would be awesome if we had a way to pull that into, like, an earlier stage, but what we call a prospect
Is
A company that we want to do business with that we don't have
any relationship with, or any lead, or any opportunity to go do business with them yet.
Okay.
So, like, I have my guys work on
prospecting lists, but that's basically what you guys would know about like
Correct, correct. Yeah.
Cold calling or cold not being on facilities. Now
I'm glad you actually asked that because we don't
we kind of keep prospects as like a pre-category, and we don't. That's another thing that we don't have everything in one spot. So like everything you know, I'm already frustrated that is in a bunch of spots
Prospecting is another thing we haven't even talked about yet.
It starts even earlier. So where we where we do start actually in one of our CRMs
Tracking is
The like lead stage or opportunity stage. And
Like a… when we start something, it… we call it a unqualified lead, which might mean somebody called in, somebody responded to an ad, somebody emailed us
Somebody found us through our website, and it just comes in as an what we call an unqualified lead
The
And really, we'll start here in this unqualified lead section
So then our team would reach out to it. Make some form of contact. We would know that it's a serious intent opportunity and we would schedule it as a meeting
or qualified lead, this is shrunk on my screen, because I'm working off of my bigger screen. Actually
Let me swap which screen I've got this on and which screen I've got
Because it'll
make this view maybe bigger for you. Did that move over? Are you able to see my screen still?
Yeah, it's slightly zoomed out
Okay.
So
Yeah, so something would come in
As an unqualified lead
Our team would reach out to it once they qualify it, it moves over to meetings scheduled, or qualified lead
And then, ideally in the way that maybe this pipeline kind of manages the whole rest of the platform we're building, like once a meeting is scheduled, we could book it on a salesperson's calendar directly. And then
Once they have the meeting, then it would move to like I would love an automated, like, checklist that's like, here's your checklist for the site visit or sales call we call going to see a client
We use two words interchangeably, site visit, which usually is more of a commercial industrial term, or sales call, which is more of a residential term.
So
Meeting scheduled means they're getting ready for a site visit slash sales call. So ideally that would
You know, the stage is kind of the trigger that gives them the reminders and gives them the checklists that they want. So then they… they get the reminder checklist of, oh, it's a residential, you know, it was tagged as a residential lead. So you get this residential checklist
It was tagged as a industrial lead. So you get it auto populates this
industrial site visit checklist, and then they go do the
meeting, and ideally, somehow have a, like, auto-form, and this would be places where, like, Stefan and U2 would be probably really helpful, but instead of my guys just going, oh, it's a industrial site visit, and I got to take a piece of paper
Write all the information down, then make sure I get somebody else the notes. It would be awesome to just
have an auto-populated
Do a form that they fill out while they're there, whether it's through, like, Google Forms, or whether it's something that we can build that lives inside of
This platform
Correct.
As a category under the deal or opportunity or whatever we call this whole thing.
But anyway, so they would fill out a certain checklist and gather certain information at the site visit. They would collect certain pictures, they would ask certain questions and all that should get logged
Under what they gathered at the site visit
Then it's going to move to this stage here, quoting, estimating
and ideally, based on the type of
opportunity that they've selected it is, whether it's residential, commercial, or industrial, it's going to populate certain type of reminders, certain type of estimating forms, maybe even
Like AI suggests based on something we've trained, like
Hey, do you think it's this type of floor system option or
Do you want to override it and manually, you know, pick the Floor System spec or whatever? So that would be the estimating piece. And we would also want to pull in that stage like our price book and
I'll show you the price book when we jump over to Housecall Pro.
Sure
Would it be more helpful if I stay in HubSpot and show you all the HubSpot stuff, or if I actually show you how we have to use this, and how fragmented it is, so that you guys go, oh, I see why this is frustrating, because at this stage
We would move over to Housecall Pro and manually read double entry things
Yep. I think
Well, would you rather see it
Okay, so
Okay.
I think it would be better if you actually show how you actually do it because exactly as you mentioned, we get an idea if it's really fragmented, and that's kind of a frustration point, that, you know, we can help solve. And actually, based on that, just a question
How a lead, like, from unqualified and qualified, and how it's moving through the pipeline or the stages, I'm assuming right now it's all, like, manual process that someone is actually moving from stage to stage, right?
Okay.
Correct. And another problem doing stuff manually isn't ideal, but the bigger problem with that is
lack of people following the process we actually need them to follow
Correct, correct. Yeah, yeah
Part of that problem, though, I understand, is because I have them operating on two systems, plus how we're prospecting and tracking that. So
The frustration isn't necessarily at my guys all the time for not following the program. It's maybe just more indicative that our system sucks, and that's why I'm asking you guys to help us fix it. But yeah.
Yes.
For sure, absolutely. Yeah, because there's also an opportunity to automate it. Like, as you were saying, like, something like happens, like a Google form, it populates with a checklist, right? So it basically reduces that human overhead and it can be automated, which can
buy back more time for you for the business, basically, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, and even, you know, fully automation, I don't think necessarily is probably even an option, but even just built-in reminders of like
Oh hey, BJ, you know, sales rep, you had a site visit, you have a site visit for tomorrow. Make sure you
You know, fill out this checklist, this checklist, and get these pictures. And then once he does it
Then it moves to the next stage and says, you know, hey, good job, and now you got to do XYZ. Like, just… just even automated reminders
Correct, correct, yeah
Yep.
That you know my my guys are still going to have to manually do some things, but if they follow a really clear like
Yeah
hey, here's what your next step is, do this and this and this, like, we're gonna get 100 times more
actual implementation.
Got it, yeah. No, that makes sense, yeah.
But, so yeah, once… once a site visit is done, and we technically go into the quoting estimating stage, which we would jump over to Housecall Pro, which… did that come over? Do you guys see my Housecall Pro different screen
Okay.
Yeah, I think Dennis Frost, yeah.
Yep.
Yep, yep, so what we would actually do, we would come into Housecall Pro
And I would have to
Or my guys would have to now go to new
And
Manually recreate
a customer
And then once that customer is done, then they have to
So they have to put customer information in, which would be, like, just contact
So in HubSpot, it's called a contact, and Housecall Pro, it's called the customer
Yeah.
So, we'd have to come manually create a customer
And then we would go to
The estimating feature against the customer, so we'll do
I don't know, a restaurant brand that we service called Egg Harbor here. So I'll pull up the
Customer file, and then I'll show you how we go into estimating
And probably back to initial question you asked
if everything was called a contact
That probably makes sense. Or contact slash customer maybe
But then off of each contact slash customer, we want to be able to create specific opportunities
So even that is kind of confusing, because, like, if it's a homeowner
The customer and the
Opportunity or project is the same thing. But
Hmm.
for a commercial or industrial project, we might have Qdoba as the customer, and then we might have 50 different projects that we
Or what's one you guys, what's that coffee? Thornton's is, is that your coffee brand up in Canada?
Certainly, but, like,
Yeah.
Okay, I just… I don't know if you know the restaurant that I mentioned, so like McDonald's, let's say, like, McDonald's is a contact of ours. We might have, you know 10 projects or 100 projects that we work on, so we need to be able to store like the master
Potential client name or info, but then we'll have, like.
deals that come off of that
Of that particular client, basically. Right? Yeah
Yeah
Just one, yeah
Yeah, if it's commercial or industrial, but the trick is if it's residential, it's usually just one just one. And even on that topic, one thing I hate about CRMs is
If you go search for something in a contact or customer
You just see the contact info, and you don't see the deals, necessarily. So somehow I would like
I would like to, whatever we create together, I would love for
Yep.
whatever that word is, customer or client or opportunity, like, there to be something central and foundational about it, but it's not like
Yeah.
Like in HubSpot, your contacts are one thing, and your deals are another, and they don't really talk together. Like, one is just a database, and then you have to go somewhere else to find anything relevant
I see what you mean, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
And I can't tell you how many times guys will be like, oh, I can't find that one. And I'll be like
I know I just saw it and then I'm like, oh, you're searching in contacts, you need to be searching in deals
Indeed, oh, okay, okay.
So, anyways
It is making like a central organization system where if you… because since they're like similar, especially as we give an example for industrial, there can be multiple deals related to one client
Yep.
So it needs to be all centralized and organized properly, basically.
Correct.
Yeah, like, I really don't… and I mean, this is a huge function of it, but I didn't even think of this one, like, I really don't want a contact spot and a deal spot. I want one name that we come up with that everything lives in
Yep, yep.
And
Then… it all
Flows… like… like, I think my off-the-cuff idea, like, I would rather have contacts as a stage in the deal flow pipeline
which also prospects could live there like instead of having prospects as some side thing, contacts as some side thing, and then our deal flow pipeline
It would be nice to be able to pull in, like, prospecting lists that we update.
contact lists that are, like, past customers, all that, and that's just a stage
And then, like
We can move things around based on what we're actually doing with that contact, but in the same view. So if my guys looked at it, like, back to
Back to this.
If we just had a contact stage and a prospecting stage, then when something actually
Someone actually expresses interest, we can move it over as an unqualified lead or a meeting scheduled, or quoting or… but it's all in one, like, congruent
Yep.
pipeline that based on what we're moving it into
It
You know, works into those workflows and reminders and stuff
With that said, as I'm talking out loud
The problem that I could foresee would be
Like, with
I'll just use McDonald's, because I know you know about that brand, but… and we actually don't, in real life, do much with McDonald's, but same example would apply to other
Like
Companies
Like, we might do 10 projects at McDonald's
And we couldn't just have, like, one
That's probably why they keep contacts and projects different, but
Ideally, everything would be in one central database
Yep.
And then, like, if we pull something out of contacts into these other things, maybe it
It says like McDonald's project
Denver. And then if we pull it out again, it's we gotta, you know name it something specific, but it'd be like McDonald's project, Alberta. But I just hate the idea of
That's great, yeah.
Yep, yep.
Contacts and all your opportunities you're actually working being separate, so… I don't know, if in the pipeline view, maybe contacts was its own anchor
Prospects was its own other anchor, and those are kind of like the pre-stages, but we can do it all in one view. And then as we pull stuff out
It stays in the contact or prospect stage
But also then we it like auto-populates, like, okay, you're pulling from the contact of McDonald's. Now you have to name which specific project opportunity this relates to
And we'll be in two detail there, is this helpful?
No, I think this is help, this is really helpful, and especially
Just so you know, actually, this is, like, standard
Best practice in these enterprise level softwares
And I feel like what the gap is basically because you're now using multiple platforms
Which are built for different use cases, which are not really aligning to your business requirements, right? Because let's say HubSpot is a more general
Yeah.
CRM platform that basically is applicable to everyone, right, who uses it. But of course, each business, let's say, like yourself, you have some specifications, because based on how you operate in the business, of course, and which is not being accounted for in here, and also HubSpot Pro. So, no, 100%.
But as you're explaining it, like, the hierarchy that you're saying, that there should be like one client, like one brand, and under that multiple deals, and also, like, multiple leads, like, you know, the hierarchy system, that's like standard best practice in, like, custom enterprise level solutions
Okay.
Yeah, this is not a problem
Yeah.
Okay.
Because yeah, this is standard practice because this adds to the user experience, right? User being yourself as a business owner who's going to use it basically they want to make it easier for you, of course. Yeah, so 100%. This is really helpful, yes.
Okay, and also
We're not yet to the stage. If we… if I was only trying to accomplish everything I explained so far, HubSpot would be a pretty great
solution, and we wouldn't be having this conversation. But the part we're about to shift into
I think, I mean, I've looked into customizing HubSpot to do all our scheduling, do all our project management, do all that stuff. And
Yeah, yeah, yep, yep.
I think it would be just as affordable to just build our own custom platform. The part we're about to get into now is the reason HubSpot is not the standalone solution
Got it.
Yeah, yeah.
But the part we've covered so far is the reason Housecall Pro is not the one-stop solution. So, anyways, yeah, thanks for bearing with me on all the details and side trails we're getting into, but
Once we get to the quoting estimating, the way we're doing it, and we go over to Housecall Pro, my guys create a customer, then they go to estimate
That's right.
In that new… in that customer, and
So… oh, great, this is gonna make me. Those are actual projects. Let me let me pick a customer that we don't actually do anything with because I don't want to
Clutter this up
So, just to clarify, you would only create a new customer in Housecall Pro when you're at that stage for estimating, if that's like a new customer, for example, correct?
Correct. If it's somebody that we've done
The only thing we use Housecall Pro for is
estimating through the rest of the project. So a customer gets created in Housecall pro. If we have a real project to bid and everything else we've always kept out of Housecall pro. But then the problem is, we don't have an organized pipeline. We're not following up with past clients
Or people that expressed interest
That then said, oh, you know what, we delayed our project, and we don't have like an organized place
that we're using everything in one spot to say, like, oh, hey, we bid, 20 different $100,000 plus jobs last year that those projects got delayed, and now we're putting those in its own category, and we're
Following up appropriately and making sure that when that project does
Get a budget and gets approved again that we're actually keeping track of it. So we're there's a lot of some of the stuff sounds real simple, but the function of making it better is going to make us a lot more effective
Yeah.
Help us make a lot more money. But yeah, in House Call Pro, we're only ever creating a customer when it's actually time to make an estimate
Yep.
Yeah.
And then with a client that is a repeat client, we wouldn't have to remake a customer the next time they want to do a project together. We because they're already
Yep.
They're already created
So this one is an example one. So this is what I'm going to use so I don't mess anything up. So let's pretend I just created a customer, and now I'm going to go create an estimate
So the estimate part
I'll show you the way we're doing it. But pretty much all of these stages would be awesome to have
You know, some automations that say, hey, remember to do this. Hey, here's the information on this type of floor system. All that stuff. So
So we are going to go create an estimate and we will
Why is this looking weird?
I'm gonna make a new client that's fake for this specific exercise
And
Test
Clients
And then I would
Create customers, so that's how we create a customer.
And then… so now we've got a brand new fake client, and then I would go to estimate
And
Create from scratch. So here we are, ready to start our estimate.
And then I'm going to
Title it
Whatever floor system option that I'm going to be doing
So I'll do
kitchen, flooring, fake
Restaurant
Area one
So now we're gonna
That's going to categorize it as this is the area that we're bidding. And then we're going to add our service and
Then we will pull from a preset
A preset
Like, Floor system
And that one's showing zero. Let's do this one.
So we'll pick our service
And it'll pull up
What type of floor system we're doing.
That one is not auto-populating a price, so let's say flake
Okay, so we're going to pick a
Standard floor system
It's gonna
pre-populate a suggested unit price. It's going to pre-populate
Ideally, like
photo that's attached to that type of floor system that we're selling. It's going to pre-populate a description of that
I can also manually add things in like
You know
Do area XYZ exclude
You know,
Bathrooms
Up to not to exceed
X amount of square foot
Night work
Now we'll shut down. Any notes, obviously, that I want to put
And then, like, I would go up here and put like 25
Units, which would be
So let's say it was
200 square foot and 250 linear foot
But of Cove, which gives us 250 total units.
All that good stuff, and then I can add
A second
Whatever
Just pick something, it'll auto-populate that
And then I can also go and add
Options like let's say, let's say we're talking about the same area
But they wanted two different price ranges, like two different types of
Options to compare price versus quality. So we'll say that one was best option
And it was a certain type of floor system. Then we're going to go to
Create another option and we'll do option two.
Budget
Friendly kitchen solution
Whatever type of system.
And then we'll save that, and we'll do the same exercise, but when the proposal goes out, it'll show option 1 versus Option 2. Sometimes we just present one option. Sometimes we
Might bid 3 different
floors at the same facility, so instead of like if we're doing if we're bidding 2 different types of options for the same space, we would do it like option one, option 2. If we're doing it
Like, 3 different areas that the same company is considering doing. We might do like
Kitchen
And then
Follow
Why is it not
Wait, that's because I'm not doing it right.
Like we might
Categorize it as one area. Oh, no, that's okay, so we can do like option one and option two for the same area, but then we could add like
Back kitchen as an option. It's calling it option, but then we would
We can use the option feature to either give, like, two or three
quotes for the same area, or we can use it to say, this is for one area, this is for one area, this is for one area. And
Because often we're bidding multiple spaces inside the same facility.
And then whichever way that all comes together
when I'm done with what I want, I go over to present
And then it shows us our
The options we picked or the places that we bid, it would
If I did it right, it would show, like, a total price
It would populate
If I pick the right, things, ideally there'd be cover photos for each type of floor system.
And then we would go to
Send it
And then it would
Ask me who… it would, like, pre-populate the client's email address, give a little
You know, show you what the email subject line is going to be that I can also edit. Show you a little delivery message.
and do all that good stuff.
And I can also pull, like, some real ones and forward them to you if it's helpful to look at, like, how it comes through. But that would all be the
estimating piece then moves right into the proposal delivery piece.
And again, there should be certain things that, like, once we finish estimating and go to this, it should say, like, hey, salesman, did you get approval from your head of projects? Did you
Do… did you upload these notes? Did you do this? Which reminds me, I'm not going to send this, and then I'm going to come down here
And there's a place to put private notes for when our crew or an operations director wants to
Look at stuff. There's a place to say, hey, I want to add a checklist that the crew can see, but the client that's going to get this proposal can't see.
So ideally, in the estimating piece we're able to upload any checklists. We're able to upload any photos. We're able to put notes for internal use only that are
For the crew, for the
projects, head of projects, whatever. Then we present it and send the proposal and then we
We would need to have a feature that we build that goes with the proposal that allows the client to accept it
sign it. Once they do that, we should get a notification back that a project was awarded, and then we would
Move to schedule it
And there should be a, you know, once something is awarded, we should get notifications that says, hey, this project was awarded
Reminder, you need to schedule it
And then we would put it on the schedule
And then we should get another reminder that says
Remember to assign your crew leader and remember to assign your project manager. And then once they get it, they would inherit all the notes and all the checklists and all the photos that we attach at that earlier stage
And then it would live on a schedule
So
back to showing you how we actually use it, then we would
track this and go, okay, so that moved to proposal delivered, great. That moved to whoops.
You know, and sometimes after we deliver a proposal, we find out, oh, that project is delayed, so we would move it to that stage. Which ideally, if we move something to that stage, we should get a notification or we when we move it to that stage, it should say
Set a reminder for yourself and we shouldn't be able to get out of that. My guy shouldn't be able to get out of that screen until they set a reminder for whatever information they got. If the client said, you know what, we thought we were going to do this this year and
We realize we're not going to do this till 2029
Then we should set a reminder to reach out
You know, midway through 2028 or whatever. So it would get moved to whatever stage is most
Relevant. One of them after
We've delivered the proposal, you know, there's inevitably some manual communication, maybe a phone call or two, and maybe we know it's likely to be awarded, but it's not awarded yet. So then it would move to a certain stage, and then our guys would really work out of this and make sure they're really on top of this one
And then
You know, let's say we get a phone call, and they said it was awarded, and we say, awesome, I need you to go into the proposal we sent you and click
You know accept contract, sign contract, all that stuff, then it would officially be
awarded here, which we would go back over to Housecall Pro and make sure it gets on the schedule
Hmm
And then, you know, project scheduled
So we can
You know, if we're viewing the pipeline, we can just look, oh, these are all the projects that are on the schedule, but then there's a schedule itself that we can look at and go, okay, here's what the guys are doing for these next five days. Here's what crews here. Here's what crews on this one.
And we would go back to Housecall Pro and we would be able to see, okay, Keith is leading the job. He's assigned as a crew leader. It's this project. We go into it.
Or the guys go into it and we want to
But that same, like, checklist and
Installation plan and
All of that stuff are here.
Once it's scheduled, we would want project management to get notifications that are like, hey, this job's three weeks away. Make sure you order the right… make sure you order material
And
Maybe if we had an AI feature built in, it could go, Hey, it's this floor system
And based off of what you guys put in the estimating sheet, which I haven't showed you yet, you know, here's what you need to order for this job. But once… once something's assigned, the cruiser… the crew guys are gonna go here and see, okay, here's the notes, here's the pictures from the site visit
Here's
Let's see
There should be stuff assigned like, here's the product spec, here's the this. Okay, here's all the information that was relevant that we need to that you actually here's what we sold. So this is what we need to prepare to actually go install 1680 foot of
This type of product. All that stuff.
When we actually are
Building. So I showed you the price book feature. I didn't and which is a category underestimating. I didn't actually show you
A
Estimating template which are
Oh
Super manual right now and just out of
That's just living on like a Google Sheet
Yep.
So… that's an oversimplified one. Hold on a second.
Sorry, just as I thought, I mean.
I'm still trying to understand that. And this is nothing, like, forward you were showing. This is just I'm thinking out loud, just trying to understand what is really the feature that really distincts Housecall Pro
It's
To be used because I feel like this technically should all be in one system, because it's not a good experience.
Yes.
Probably the price book
And the ability to send a proposal have it awarded or approved by the client
Yeah.
Okay.
And then have it come back to our schedule. Also, quickbooks
is integrated, so when something gets awarded, then we know, okay, great, we're gonna invoice for a down payment. But really the like
The ability to upload pictures and notes and stuff, send a proposal
Get it awarded, and then schedule it
Hmm.
is currently the feature. It's not
I mean, you're absolutely right. It's not great by any means, but there's stuff
In the like
price book
Schedule piece that I know how to do in HubSpot
One thing I… so
Here's an estimating sheet
Yep.
I mean, we built these all ourself, and I'm sure we can simplify and build them better, but it would be awesome if that lived inside of this
Platform as a
Place where we can go and customize it and it automatically is part of the
Yeah
Yep.
deal we're working on, instead of living in its own spot. So, yeah, I told you we had two systems, but really, we've got HubSpot, we've got HubScope Pro, we've got
estimating going on on Google Sheets, and then we move back into Housecall pro to finish the estimate and get the proposal out.
But so
Here's a Google sheet of residential flake floor estimating sheet
Back to House Call Pro, if we actually go to the price book feature
We can pick certain types of
Systems that we use a lot
Set our
kind of standard pricing
Put pictures around it. So whatever we customize here is what
populates that auto description and price and stuff in that services category that I
It was really complicated trying to explain.
So, whatever the price book is… like, what we're gonna build needs a price book feature that's kind of the standard template for
What you know once in the estimating feature, we select it's this kind of system, it would auto populate description with a picture, with a
Oversimplified square foot price that then our guys would customize a little bit based on
What our estimating worksheet that we did in Google actually looked like. This feels so confusing saying it. I hope I'm not
No
Driving you guys crazy, or… chasing the heck out of you.
It's kind of embarrassing, actually, speaking it out loud on how bad and how unorganized this is.
But
I definitely feel your pain when you were talking about, like, the fragmentation, which is, you're absolutely correct, that the system is right now like your workflow with… it's like, you're right, it sounds it sounds like the good user experience would be like everything to be in one platform, because that's how everything is going in flow
Yep.
Yep. Yeah.
But the flow is basically broken and getting fragmented because they're like different third party players and there's some manual work involved as well with the estimate sheet, for example
Yep, yep
Okay.
So I mean, I feel the pain point now for sure, but that can definitely be, like, as I said, it's definitely possible to customize it into, like, one solution that is one stop shop for your entire business. That's definitely possible
Yeah
Okay, so one other thing that we didn't talk about yet is
Our picture feature
Okay.
So I'm going to go back to this fake one we just did and
In Housecall Pro
It there's two ways we can get pictures in here. But ideally
the pictures that our salesperson took at that site visit or appointment are all already stored here, so that when we go to estimating
Whoever is actually estimating it can see what the site conditions look like. What we're looking at if it's
an existing project, if it's a new build, instead of pictures, we would have architectural plans, and those would be stored against the
Opportunity that we're working. But
Right now, we either have to upload pictures
Custom or manual as attachments or
There is something called CompanyCam, which for some reason is not,
Oh, it's because
Yeah, here we go.
So
All right
So, CompanyCam, that's like the photo capture application
That's a photo capture application and on that specific one, I actually like CompanyCam a lot
Okay.
As long as we can make it integrate with… like, we don't need to go build a photo app. But it would need to
Like if this
finishes loading, I can show you how
This works, if I can find the right one
This one
So Housecall Pro, you can either manually upload photos, which
It's kind of a pain in the butt.
But we have done it for a long time, or
Here's another problem I don't like Housekeep Pro. I keep not finding what I'm looking for because like if I just go into estimates, it doesn't show me everything that happened after estimates.
Yeah.
I'm actually looking for
Right now
I'm just looking in the estimate part, but I'm missing everything that actually happened when this job happened. And I would love to
Yeah, yeah.
Separate that fragmentation out. Kind of the same idea where, like, a contact is so separate from the actual project. Well, in HouseCall Pro, like, if I go and look for something in estimates
I don't see anything that happened
Yeah, yeah.
After that, and I've got to, like, look in the right spot, and it just creates a lot of user
Sure.
So now
It should be all connected, yeah.
Yeah, I think
See, I'm not even finding
What I'm trying to show you guys, which
Oh, for sure.
It's not good for your time efficiency right now, but it does maybe help you feel my pain. So I really, I really want to find this and show you guys so
I'm going to go back into the schedule and then get back into the job itself that I'm looking for
And then I will be able to show you this photo feature. So here we go.
Okay, so right here, these are all uploaded as attachments
Some of these, probably the guys took on their phone and then had to manually update, but some of them, they probably took through CompanyCam. And company cam, the way it syncs with Housecall Pro is really good that it'll, it'll like find the project
just by location, and you don't need to go tell it what projects you're doing or anything. The guys just open company cam on their phone, take a picture, and it will
Make sure it finds its way to the right project based on the location of the picture being taken.
And this is the company cam, or this is the house called Pro view of it
If I go over to the actual company cam app
I can search things by project
And my guys don't really go into company cam
In and of itself, they just open the app and take a picture, and then it finds its way to Housecall Pro.
Which would be awesome if we could
Like, I don't expect you guys to
Build a
photo app here for us. So
See, so look, I created that fake one in Housecall Pro and it created a project inside a company cam that now when my guys go open it.
And take a picture if they're within proximity to that fake address I gave it, it'll automatically take the picture that they took and put it there. But this
Where's the Egg Harbor one that I was wanting to look at?
Okay, so the
Egg Harbor estimate or project here that I'm looking at.
If we
Okay.
Sorry, Nick, I'm just going to turn off my video, but I'm listening, so you just continue. Sorry about that. Yeah
Yeah, so if I
It's calling it Grandma Helen because that was the name that we put that was a personal name that we put under the Egg Harbor account, but like these are all pictures of the Egg Harbor job that I was trying to show you. And
Like, ideally, my salesman starts to take pictures while they're doing just the site visit. Those all get stored against it, and we're just building a log
We would be doing step-by-step pictures and going all the way through from, you know, showing up at a messy job site to completed floor
And
In a perfect world, it's all sinking against the project and being stored there.
Once a job is done
We would mark it as complete, and then it would move to
Our accounting department to like invoice, make sure we're closing the project out properly. There should be some notifications of like
Make sure the customer signs off on this. Make sure, you know, it should ask questions like, were there any change orders or additional scope items that happened during that project on this one, there actually was, but we don't have a feature to
Automate that question. We're just we got to remember. Oh, hey, they added this and this on that job, and I need to go change what we actually invoice them for. But yeah, after the
Projects complete, it moves to the accounting administration side. They close the project out, invoice for it. It integrates with our QuickBooks. It gets
When we get paid
You know.
should ideally market as paid here
somehow because it you know QuickBooks says it was paid, so it should say it's paid here or whatever. Their house call pro does that or somewhere between QuickBooks and Housecall Pro. We don't have to redundantly do that or duplicate that. It just gets paid to our bank account
And somehow, if it's marked paid in QuickBooks, then it automatically marks it as paid here.
And
So, sorry, our question, just going back to
Yep.
Yes.
Company CAM, right? Is that, like, a third-party application that you have signed up separately and then integrated with Housecall Pro? Is that how it works? Okay, got it, okay.
Yep.
Okay, okay, cool. Because actually, I know you were mentioning that you don't want, like, us to build, like, a photo capture app, because building that is, like, not too complicated, to be honest. Yeah.
Yeah
Oh, well, I mean, if there's a way to do that, I just figured it was super complicated. I mean, the more simplified and in one spot
Yep, yep.
Yeah.
Everything lives the easier my life and business and everybody else's is
Yeah, for sure. Yeah.
I just don't want to ask you guys to do things that… if 95% of it is, like, you're like, yeah, that's super doable, and then I'm like, oh, I want this too, and you're like, okay, that
Is
Yeah, yeah
Crazy. You know, so
Yeah, no, for sure, for sure. Yeah
Like if… the reason I said that about company cam is because
Yeah.
As long as the guys take a picture through that, it automatically finds its way back there and the guys don't ever have to go
Log into CompanyCam. Get on here, upload photos. So like, I think I'd be a little naive if
Yeah.
I thought you guys were gonna build everything custom. So if if you can on the photo thing, sweet. But if you can do 95%, and you're just like, yeah, you still have to have a house called pro company camp subscription, and your technicians and sales guys have to have it on your phone, their phone
You just got to tell them to take the picture, and it'll still sync over and store against the actual opportunity project we're working on
Yep, yep.
Great, if you guys can do it better, then even better. On that kind of same line.
You know, if we had a
If our two pre-actual pipeline categories were prospects and contacts
prospects would be somebody we want to get in touch with that we're not in touch with
Correct.
Contacts would be somebody that we have been in touch with, have done a project with, and then we're pulling out into the actual
Sales to projects, pipeline stages from there. But kind of like on the same line of company cam. If our prospects, if we use like Apollo to
Create lists and pull them in
That's great. I don't expect you guys to, like, rebuild Apollo, but if we could somehow integrate Apollo, pull information there that drops into our
prospect stage, and then my guys can go in here and work off of it, call off of it, go, oh, hey, we made contact, and they do want a
project, then it would get moved from Prospect to contact
and we could then create off of that contact a project that we're looking at
Yep.
So in the
Sorry, just show a quick question. I don't want to ask that question reading your document about Apollo. Is that just like a lead scraping tool, or what do you use Apollo? Right? Okay, okay.
Yeah. So like if I go, okay, I want to find every food and beverage manufacturing facility within
200 miles of this
Yep, yep
city
Yeah, pull all of those, and then I can go, okay, I want every maintenance director at
Yep.
all of those facilities and then it'll pull all those into a spreadsheet with their mobile and their… it's a… it's a data scraping tool
Correct, correct, yeah, yeah.
And
But if there was a way to, you know, integrate it just like
Yep.
company cam, and go, okay, we're gonna… in our project stage.
I'm sorry, in our prospecting stage, we want to… and it would be awesome if we could do this part, and just in the background, Apollo work like
When we go to our prospecting stage, we just type in, we want food and beverage facilities within 60 miles of this location. And then it grabs all that and pulls it into the prospecting stage. And now my guy can work out of
Yep.
Okay, I'm going to call or email these 100 contacts and then, oh, three of them said they want us to come look at a job. So now they move to contacts because we've actually established a
Some level of interest
And then off of that, we could move it into, you know, meeting scheduled in the pipeline, and then follow it all the way through. So I think
Okay
That would… those would be the, like, pre-pipeline stages, and then the pipeline, we could call it, like
Okay.
Lead the projects pipeline or something, and then each each stage would need to be named appropriately, but each of them would just have their own each pipeline stage category would just each have its own set of reminders
The other thing
Would be everything we just said would have to have
Each location that we're gonna put on would have to have their own pipeline
Okay.
That shouldn't master pipeline per location, but then off of that
Just like in this one, we would want to have the ability to assign
A owner
Yeah.
To that, which would be a, like, assign a salesperson, assign a project manager. So like
this oil company
Sorry, sorry, Nick, to cut you off. I do have another meeting that I need to jump to
Yeah, yeah, I better let you run. Sorry. Yeah, hopefully
Yeah. No, no, no, I think this has been really helpful. If there's more, I guess, stuff remaining that we need to know, we can definitely book, like, a part two of it, and then we can continue, but depends on
Yeah
Okay.
This… this covered 90% of it, and the main thing is this pipeline kind of being the
Oh, thank you again
the thing that runs the rest of all these features, and then us building certain reminders and things per stage. But yeah, sensitive of your time. Thank you very much. You guys are doing great on this. Thanks for bearing with me, and I hope your next meeting
goes good, and we can… we can touch base in email and keep it going from here.
For sure. Yeah, I think we will get started off of the information you shared today. If I have more questions, I'll reach out to you over email, but we'll get started off like just speccing out the scope and everything on our end.
Perfect.
Awesome. Thank you, guys. You guys are great. Thanks.
Awesome. Thanks, Nick, for your time. Thank you.
Thank you. Bye.
Thanks, Zach. Bye.